A Guide to the Records of the Ki-Wives of Arlington Virginia, 1951-2000
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
Records of the Ki-Wives of Arlington Virginia, 1951-2000
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
RG 98
10 boxes.
Arlington Ki-Wives
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlington Ki-Wives Vice President Blanche Kirchner in 2000.
Historical Information
The Ki-Wives of Arlington was founded in 1951 as a sister organization to the Arlington Kiwanis Club. Like the Kiwanis Club, the Ki-Wives sought to foster good will and fellowship among members, who were wives of Kiwanis members, and to provide the means to render altruistic service and to build a better community. Also in 1951, the Council of Ki-Wives was founded as an umbrella organization of local Ki-Wives Clubs. Its name became Ki-Wives National in 1964 and Ki-Wives International in 1975.
With dwindling membership in the 1980s and 1990s, the Arlington club disbanded at the end of May 2000.
Scope and Content
Record Group 98 houses the official records of the Arlington, Virginia, branch of Ki-Wives International, dating 1951-2000. Also included are some incomplete unofficial records of Ki-Wives International, dating 1964-2000. The record group measures approximately five linear feet.
The Arlington club's records document the club's activities, including luncheon meetings with presentations on civic topics and fundraising activities such as bazaars, fashion shows, and progressive dinners. Correspondents include a few regional and national political figures that the club contacted as potential speakers, such as Ivy Baker Priest (1956) and Patricia Nixon (1957). The club then donated the money earned to a variety of Arlington and Northern Virginia charities such as the Salvation Army, Hospice of Northern Virginia, and the Arlington Food Assistance Center. The correspondence includes many thank-you letters from such organizations. In 1956, the Ki-Wives began to sponsor Keyettes Clubs, service organizations for high school girls, and the records of both the local and national groups reflect this work.
Types of material include: bylaws, minutes, financial records, correspondence, newsletters, officers' and committee reports, clippings, photographs, and a scrapbook (ca. 1970-ca. 1990). The entire scrapbook, which contained photographs, clippings, and paper memorabilia, has been photocopied. Subsequently the photographs were removed for preservation storage.
The Ki-Wives International portion of the collection document its relationship with its branches, with some bylaws, minutes, and activity reports from the branches.
Arrangement
Record Group 98 is organized into seven series by type of material. The first six series are different types of administration records for the Arlington Ki-Wives, while Series 7 contains records from Ki-Wives International. Arrangement within series is generally chronological, with Series 3, Financial Records, being divided into five subseries, and Series 4, Officers and Committees, arranged alphabetically by committee name.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
RG 102, Kiwanis Club of Arlington Records, and RG 197, South Arlington Kiwanis Club Records, document the activities of the local Arlington Kiwanis.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Women -- United States -- Societies and clubs.; Women in community organization; Kiwanis International; Arlington (Va.); Arlington County (Va.)
Contents List
- Constitution, Bylaws and Policies
  - Constitution and Bylaws, n.d., 1961-1998 (Box 1)
  - Song, Policies, n.d., 1961-1998 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Regular Treasurer's Reports
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1951-1954 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1955-1957 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1958 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1959 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1972 (Box 1)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1977-1980 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1985-1987 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1998 (Box 2)
  - General and Executive Meeting Minutes, Agendas, Treasurer's Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
- Financial Records
  - Annual Treasurer's Reports
    - Annual Treasurer's Reports, 1953-1974 (Box 3)
    - Annual Treasurer's Reports, 1975-1999 (Box 3)
  - Bank Statements
    - Bank Statements, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
    - Bank Statements, 1989-1993 (Box 3)
    - Bank Statements, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
    - Bank Statements, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
  - Check Books
    - Check Books, 1987-1990 (Box 3)
    - Check Books, 1991-1994 (Box 3)
  - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists
    - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists, n.d., 1983-1986 (Box 3)
    - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists, 1987-1990 (Box 3)
    - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
    - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists, 1994-1996 (Box 3)
    - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
    - Bills, Receipts, Contribution Lists, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
  - Membership Dues and Lists
    - Membership Dues and Lists, 1953-1983 (Box 4)
    - Membership Dues and Lists, 1984-1988 (Box 4)
    - Membership Dues and Lists, 1989-1993 (Box 4)
    - Membership Dues and Lists, 1994-1997 (Box 4)
    - Membership Dues and Lists, 1998-2000 (Box 4)
- Officers and Committees
  - Officer Lists, 1955-1998 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report of the President, 1951-1980 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report of the First Vice President, 1953-1972 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report of the Recording Secretary, 1952-1972 (Box 4)
  - Annual Report of the Corresponding Secretary, 1952-1972 (Box 4)
  - Committee Preference Surveys, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Bake Sale Committee, 1986-1989 (Box 5)
  - Bazaar Committee, 1963-1971 (Box 5)
  - Community Service Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - Fashion Show Committee, 1958-1972 (Box 5)
  - Finance and Budget Committee, 1956-1972 (Box 5)
  - History Committee, 1951-1974 (Box 5)
  - Hospitality Committee, 1954-1975 (Box 5)
  - Inter-Club Council and Committee, 1955-1966 (Box 5)
  - Inter-Service Club Council, 1969-1999 (Box 5)
  - Keyette Committee, 1960-1991 (Box 5)
  - Membership Committee, 1953-1975 (Box 5)
  - Nominating Committee, 1954-1975, 1996 (Box 5)
  - Program Committee, 1953-1975 (Box 5)
  - Progressive Dinner Committee, 1956-1998 (Box 5)
  - Publicity Committee, 1951-1975 (Box 5)
  - Quilt Committee, 1990 (Box 5)
  - Service and Welfare Committee, 1954-1972 (Box 5)
  - Telephone Committee, 1955-1970 (Box 5)
  - Ways and Means Committee, 1951-1982 (Box 5)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence, n.d., 1954-1964 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1982 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - Clippings, 1958-1991 (Box 6)
  - Photographs from the Scrapbook, 1970-1981 (1) (Box 6)
  - Photographs from the Scrapbook, 1970-1981 (2) (Box 6)
  - Photographs from the Scrapbook, 1970-1981 (3) (Box 6)
  - Photographs from the Scrapbook, 1970-1981 (4) (Box 6)
  - Photographs from the Scrapbook, 1989-1990 (Box 6)
  - Documents from the Scrapbook, 1970-1990 (Box 6)
  - Documents from the Scrapbook, 1951-1969 (1) (Box 7)
  - Documents from the Scrapbook, 1951-1969 (2) (Box 7)
  - Documents from the Scrapbook, 1951-1969 (3) (Box 7)
- Records of the Ki-Wives International
  - Charter and Bylaws of Ki-Wives National, 1964-1976 (Box 7)
  - Charter and Bylaws of Ki-Wives International, 1977-1987 (Box 7)
  - Ki-Wives National and International Officers, 1956-1999 (Box 7)
  - Ki-Wives International History and Club Song (Box 7)
  - Annual and Quarterly Reports from Branches, 1964-1988 (Box 7)
  - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1964-1986 (Box 7)
  - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1987-1991 (Box 7)
  - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1992-1996 (Box 8)
  - Meeting Agendas and Minutes, 1997-2000 (Box 8)
  - Keyettes International, 1986-1990 (Box 8)
  - Keyettes International, 1991-2000 (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Brochures, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Stationery (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Newsletters, n.d., 1978-1998 (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Correspondence, 1965-1981 (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Correspondence, 1987-1993 (Box 8)
  - Ki-Wives International Correspondence, 1994-2000 (Box 8)
- OVERSIZE BOX 1
  - Photocopy of Entire Scrapbook, 1970-1990, Felt Tote Bag, Cotton Tote Bag
- ARTIFACT BOX 1
  - Gavel, 2 Stamps, Small U.S. Flag